Guide to the History of Medicine Picture File, 1523-2002 and undated RL.00570
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- History of Medicine Picture File: People Series, approx. 1851 items
  - Osler, William, Sir, 1849-1919, "Osler at Old Blockley," color reproduction of painting by Dean Cornwell, from series "Pioneers of American Medicine, published by John Wyeth & Brother, Inc., Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, after 1940, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Depicts Osler at an elderly patient's bedside, surrounded by medical students, outdoors, in the yard of Philadelphia's Blockley Hospital, now Philadelphia General, circa 1884. Published description on back of print refers to the renovation of this building on June 8, 1940.
  - Owen, Sir Richard (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Paaw, Petrus (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Paget, James, box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Packard, Francis R. (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Paine, Martyn (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Pamphilus, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Papanicolau, G. W., 1940, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Paracelsus, 1493-1591 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Paracelsus, 1493-1591, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Pare, Ambroise (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Park, Roswell (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Parker, Peter (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Parr, Thomas (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Parrish, Joseph (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Pascal, Blaise (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Pasteur, Louis, 1822-1895 (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Pasteur, Louis, 1822-1895, box size: 16x20 inches; 2 items (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Pasteur, Louis, 1822-1895, box size: 23 x 30 inches; 2 items (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Pasteur alone in his laboratory; Pasteur vaccinating a child with a crowd of onlookers in his chambers. Includes slide.
  - Pasteur, Louis, with his grand-daughter, by Leon Joseph Florentin Bonnat, 1886, color reproduction of painting, undated, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Patterson, R. M. (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Patin, Charles, 1633-1693 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Patin, Guido (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Pattison, Granville S. (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Pavlov, Ivan P., 1849-1936 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Pearson, George, 1751-1828 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Peck, Charles Howard, 1870-1927 (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Peerless, Sidney "Skip," 1985, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Pellet, Thomas (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - Penn, Thomas (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Penrose, R. A. F. (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Pepper, William (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Pepper. William, 1843-1898, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 7)
    Includes a biography pasted on the back of the portrait.
  - Perrault, Claude (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Pettenkofer, Max Josef von, 1818-1901 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Pettenkofer, Max Josef von, 1818-1901 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Petit, Antoine (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - Petty, Sir W. (Box 7, Folder 83)
  - Pfeiffer, Richard (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Pfluger, Eduard Wilhelm, 1829-1910 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Phaneuf, Louis E., 1884-1953 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Philip, Alexander Philip Wilson, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Physick, Philip Syng (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pick, Philipp Josef (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Pilcher, Lewis Stephen (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Pinard, Adolph (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Pincus, Gregory (b. 1903) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Pinel, Philippe, 1745-1826, 2 folders (Box 8, Folder 8, 9)
    Second item is a photographic postcard reproduction of painting by T. Robert-Fleury of "Pinel, médecin en chef de la Salpêtrière, 1795." Card was published by Goupil, as "Carte-Album no. 840."
  - Pitcairn, William, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Planck, Max (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Platter, Felix (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Plempius, Vopiscus Fortunatus (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Polk, William Mecklenburg (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Poppen, James L., 1963, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Portal, Antoine (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Portraits de nos médecins contemporains (19th c. French physicians) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Modern black-and-white reproduction of card with small oval portraits of 19th century French physicians. Accompanied by photocopied list of physicians.
  - Portraits of Great American Surgeons: First Series; and Past Presidents of the American College of Surgeons, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches; 2 folders (Box 13, Folder 12)
    First Series: J.B. Deaver; D.H. Agnew; C.H. Frazier; P.S. Physick; J.W. White; W. Shippen. Past Presidents: F. Martin; C. Mayo; J.M.T. Finney; W. Mayo; G. Crile; G. E. Armstrong.
  - Pott, Percivall (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Pottenger, Francis Marion, 1869 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Pottenger, Francis Marion Jr. (b. 1901) (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Preissnitz, Vincenz, 1788-1851, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Priestley, Joseph, 1733-1804 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Priestley, J. H.?, circa 1920s (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Prout, George R. (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Pulteney, Richard, 1730-1801 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Pye, Henry Jame, 1745-1813 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Quekett, John Thomas, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Quercetanus, Josephus (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Quesnay, François (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Rabelais, François, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Rabelais, François (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Radcliffe, John (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Ramesey, William [Guglielmi] (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Ramon y Cajal, Santiago, 1852-1934 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Ramsay, David (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Ransohoff, Joseph (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Randolph, J. (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Ray, J. Christian (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Rayer, Pierre François Olive (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Recklinghausen, Friedrich D. von (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Redman, John (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Reed, Walter (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Reed, Walter, 1851-1902, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Reichert, Edward Tyson (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Reichstein, Tadeus (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Reil, Johann Christian, 1759-1813 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Reymond, Emil Du Bois, 1818-1896 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Reymond, Emil Du Bois, 1818-1896, box size: 23 x 30 inches (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Reynerus, Bontius (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Reynolds, Larry (Box 8, Folder 43)
    Radiologist, Alabama and Michigan, active mid-20th century.
  - Reynolds, Samuel Robert Means (b. 1903) (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Rich, Arnold R., 1893-1968 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Rich, Arnold R., circa 1960s, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Richerand, Anthelme Balthasar (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Richet, Charles Robert, 1850-1935 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Richter, George Gottlieb, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Riddle, Oscar (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Riegel, Franz (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Ring, John J., 1928-2010 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Riolan, Jean, 1582-1617 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Riva-Rocci, Scipione, 1863-1937 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Riverius, Lazarus (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Roentgen, Wilhelm Conrad, 1845-1923 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Roentgen, Wilhelm Conrad, 1845-1923, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches; 2 portraits (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Rokitansky, Karl, 1804-1878, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Rolleston, Humphry Davy, Sir 1862-1944 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    Staining caused by water damage on back of print, some spots on front.
  - Romberg, Ernst von (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Roosa, St. John (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Rosen, George (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Rothmund, August von (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Roux, Wilhelm (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Roux, Pierre Paul Émile, 1853-1933, circa 1899, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Rufus of Ephesus (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Rumford, Benjamin Thompson, Graf von (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813, 11 items (Box 8, Folder 63)
    Includes a photographic copy of negative, hand-colored engraving, and copy negatives.
  - Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Includes slide. Engraving, with facsimile autograph.
  - Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813, box size: 16.5x20.5 inches (Box 20, Folder 8)
    Engraved portrait of Benjamin Rush, printed on single sheet approx. 7.75x9.75 inches and in mat. Text: "To the Gentlemen of the Faculty & Medical Students throughout the United States this Plate Engraved with the Drs. Permission at the request..." (Rest has been cut off; full text from other sources is available online.) Painted by J. Paul Jr., engraved and sold by James Akin, Philadelphia, 1800. Appears to be an early 20th century reproduction, brittle and darkened. Copies are located in box 8.
  - Russell, Alexander, 1715?-1768 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Russell, Patrick, 1727-1805 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    Frontispiece portrait from Russell's work, A Continuation of an Account of Indian Serpents (1802).
  - Rutherford, John, 1695-1779 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Ruysch, Frederic (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Ruland, Johannis (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Sabin, Florence Rena, 1871-1953 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - Sabouraud, Raymond, 1864-1938 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Physician, also an amateur sculptor - created bust of M. A. (Albert) Terson (see entry).
  - Saemisch, Theodor (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - St. André, Nathaniel (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Salk, Jonas Edward (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Salmon, William, 1644-1713 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Sanger (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Santorio Santorio, 1561-1636 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Sarton, George, 1884-1956 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Saunders, William (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Saunders, William, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Saussure (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Scanzoni (von Lichtenfels), Friedrich Wilhelm (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Scarpa, Antonio (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Schech, Philipp (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Scheuchzerus, Johannes Jacobus (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Schleiden, Matthias, Jakob, 1804-1881 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Schmidt, Alexander (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Schmeideberg, Oswald (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Schönlein, Johann Lukas (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Schultze, Bernhard S. (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Schuman, Henry (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Schwann, Theodor, 1810-1882 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Schwartz, Henry Gerard, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Schweinitz, George Edmund de (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Semmelweiss, Ignaz Philipp (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Sennert, Daniel (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Servetus, Michael, 1511-1553 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Severino, Marco Aurelio (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Sevringhaus, Elmer Louis (b. 1894) (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Sharpey-Shaefer, Edward Albert, 1850-1935 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Shaw, George, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Shelton, Eberle Kost (b. 1888) (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Sherrington, Charles Scott, 1857-1952, 4 folders, 5 items (Box 9, Folder 30-33)
  - Shorr, Ephraim, 1941, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Siegemurdin, Justinen (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - Sigerist, Henry Ernest, 1891-1957 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - Silliman, Benjamin (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - Simpson, Alexander Russell (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - Simpson, James Young (Box 9, Folder 38)
  - Sims, J. Marion (Box 9, Folder 39)
  - Silvius, Jacques (Box 9, Folder 40)
  - Slemons, Josiah (Box 9, Folder 41)
  - Smellie, William (Box 9, Folder 42)
  - Smith, A. J. (Box 9, Folder 43)
  - Smith, Edward, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Smith, George van Siclen (Box 9, Folder 44)
  - Smith, Sir James Edward (Box 9, Folder 45)
  - Smith, Nathan Rymo (Box 9, Folder 46)
  - Smith, Nathan R., box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Smith, Olive Watkins (Box 9, Folder 47)
  - Smith, Philip Embry, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Smith, Theobald (Box 9, Folder 48)
  - Smith, Theobald, 2 folders (Box 9, Folder 49, 50)
  - Snellen, Herman (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Socrates, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 15)
    Engraving by Antonio Capellano after Florentine painter and engraver Giovanni Domenica Campiglia, 1800s?
  - Socrates, box size: 11x14 inches (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Soemmerring, Samuel Thomas, 1755-1830 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Solander, Daniel Charles (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Sjöqvist, Olof (Box 9, Folder 54)
  - Spalding (Box 9, Folder 55)
  - Spalding, Matthias (Box 9, Folder 56)
  - Spallanzani, Lazaro, 1729-1799 (Box 9, Folder 57)
  - Spiegel, Adriaan van den, 1578-1625, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Spicer, R. W. (Box 9, Folder 58)
  - Spurzheim, Johann Christophe (Box 9, Folder 59)
  - Stahl, Georg Ernst, 1660-1734 (Box 9, Folder 60)
  - Starling, Ernest, 1866-1927 (Box 9, Folder 61)
  - Stearns, John, 1770-1848 (Box 9, Folder 62)
  - Stecher, Robert M. (Box 9, Folder 63)
  - Stellwagen, Thomas C. (Box 9, Folder 64)
  - Stensen, Niels, 1638-1686 (Box 9, Folder 65)
  - Stewart, Thomas Grainger (Box 9, Folder 66)
  - Stille, Charles J. (Box 9, Folder 67)
  - Strudwick (Box 9, Folder 68)
  - Sudhoff, Karl (Box 9, Folder 69)
  - Sudhoff, Karl Friedrich Jakob and William H. Welch (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Swammerdam, Jan, 1637-1680, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Sydenham, Thomas (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Sydenham, John, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Sylvaticus, Benedictus (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Sylvius, Franciscus, 1614-1672 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Sylvius, Francois de la Boë, 1614-1672, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 15)
    Also referred to as Le Boë, Franciscus de.
  - Sylvius, Johannes, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Tait, Robert Lawson (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Tarnier, Etienne Stephane (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Taylor, John (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Telinde, Richard W. (b. 1894) (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Terson, M. A. (Albert) (Box 9, Folder 78)
  - Thayer, William S. (Box 9, Folder 79)
  - Thayer, William S., box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 15)
    Two copies of black-and-white print portrait.
  - Thompson, Henry (Box 9, Folder 80)
  - Thornton, Robert John (Box 9, Folder 81)
  - Thurneisser, Leonard (Box 9, Folder 82)
  - Tiedemann, Friedrich (Box 9, Folder 83)
  - Tissot, Samuel Auguste Andre David (Box 9, Folder 84)
  - Titus, Paul, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Townsend, Smith, Back of print has picture of Bliss, D. W. (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - Trent, Dr. Josiah, with Mary Duke Biddle Trent [Semans], and Dr. Erwin H. Ackerknecht (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - Trent, Dr. Josiah, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Trent, Dr. Josiah, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches; 3 items (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Two black-and-white photographic portraits, circa early 1930s and 1948, and a photograph of sculptural bust of Trent.
  - Tronchin, Théodore, 1709-1781, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Trotter, Thomas (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - Tulp, Nikolaes (born Claes Pieterszoon), 1593-1674 (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - Turner, Daniel (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Turner, Henry Hubert (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Urdang, George (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Ure, Andrew, M.D. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Valles, D. Francisco, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Valsalva, Antonio Maria (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Valverdus, Joannes (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Van Dyke, Harry B. (b. 1895) (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Van Dyke, Morton (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Veitz, Ilya (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Velpeau, Alfred-Armand-Louis-Marie, box size: 23 x 30 inches (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Une leçon de Velpeau, engraving of scene in anatomy clinic with cadaver; with name labels for other attending physicians.
  - Venner, Tobias (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Vernet, S. Gil (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Vesalius, Andreas (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Vesalius, Andreas, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 20, Folder 8)
    19th century lithograph by Salmon of engraving by Bocourt, from the painting, "André Vésale de Bruxelles," by Calcar, in the Louvre.
  - Vesalius, Andreas, box size: 16x20.5 inches (Box 20, Folder 8)
    André Vesalé, lithograph by G. Engelmann after a drawing by P. R. Vigneron, 19th century.
  - Vesalius, Andreas, box size: 16x20 inches; Color print, matted (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Vierordt, Karl, 1818-1884 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Vierordt, Oswald (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Vieussens, Raymond, 1641-1715 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Villeneuve, Arnauld de (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Virchow, Rudolf (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Von Baer, K.E. (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Von Basch, Samuel Siegfried Karl Ritter (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Voronoff, Serge (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Waksman, Feldman A. (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Waldeyer-Hartz, Wilhelm von, 1836-1921 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Waller, Augustus Desiré, 1856-1922 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Waller, Erik, 1875-1955 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Warburg, Otto Heinrich, 1883-1970 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Wardrop, James (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Warren, J. Mason, 1811-1867 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Warren, John, 1753-1815 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - Warren, John Collins (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Warren, Joseph (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Warren, Richard, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Warren, Samuel (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Waterhouse, Benjamin, 1754-1846 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Weber, Hermann (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Welch, William Henry, 1850-1934, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches; 7 items (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Three individual images of Welch; in addition, there are three copies of one of the images, dated 1930, all of which are autographed. Also includes two paper copies of encomium to Welch.
  - Wells, Horace (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Wells, John Doane (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - Wells, Thomas Spencer (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Wells, T. Spencer, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Wells, Warner Lee (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Wenckebach, Ernst August (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Wenckebach, Karel Frederik, 1864-1940 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Wepfer, Johann Jacobus (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - Wernicke, Carl (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Wharton, Thomas, 1614-1673 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Whipple, George H. (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - Whistler, William (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Widal, Fernand (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Wilkins, Lawson, 1894-1963 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Williams, John Whitridge, 2 folders (Box 10, Folder 47, 48)
  - Willis, Thomas, M.D., 1621-1675 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - Willis, Thomas, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Wilmer, William Holland, 1863-1936, 2 folders (Box 10, Folder 50, 51)
    Includes group shot of four opthalmologists: Fuchs, Parsons, Schweinitz [?], and Wilmer, 1929.
  - Wilson, Sir William James Erasmus (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - Winckel, Franz von (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Wintersteiner, Oskar, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Wistar, Caspar (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Withering, William (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - Wolff, Julius (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Wollaston, William Hyde (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Wood, Horatio Curtis (Box 10, Folder 58)
  - Woodhouse, James (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Woodville, William, box size: 20x24 inches (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Worm, Ole [or Olaus Wormius], box size: 11.5 x 15 inches (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Wotton, Henry (Box 10, Folder 60)
  - Wright, Sir Almroth, 1861-1947 (Box 10, Folder 61)
  - Wright, Marmaduke Burr, 1803-1879 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Wyeth, Florence Sims (Box 10, Folder 63)
  - Wyeth, John A. M.D., 1845-1922 (Box 10, Folder 64)
  - Wylie, Phillip, box size: 16x20 inches (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Young, Hugh H. (Box 10, Folder 65)
  - Young, Thomas, 1773-1829 (Box 10, Folder 66)
  - Zacutus, Lusitanus (Box 10, Folder 67)
  - Zahn, Friedrich Wilhelm (Box 10, Folder 68)
  - Ziegler, Ernst (Box 10, Folder 69)
  - Ziemssen, Hugo von (Box 10, Folder 70)
  - Zuckerkandl, Emil, 1849-1910 (Box 10, Folder 71)
  - Unidentified people, 2 folders, 38 items (Box 10, Folder 72, 73)
    Chiefly early to mid-20th century black-and-white portraits mounted on cardstock. In a few cases there is a last name but the individual could not be identified.
  - Unidentified people, box size: 16x20 inches; 1 item (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Unidentified male physician with bow tie, circa 1920s, black-and-white photographic reproduction; illegible signature [Pennby?]
  - Unidentified people, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches; 2 items (Box 19, Folder 6)
    Unidentified physician [William de -heder?] in lab coat, sent to Alfred Blalock, black-and-white reproduction of painting, 1946. Unidentified man, albumen photograph, Berlin, Germany, circa 1910.
  - Unidentified people, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches; 3 items (Box 19, Folder 7)
    Male in dark suit, previously identified as Pinard, Paris photographer, circa 1920s. Cannot be Adolphe Pinard.
    Male physician in Army uniform, black-and-white photograph (taken out of mat), circa 1940s.
    Male physician, black-and-white photograph mounted on board, Rochester, N.Y., circa 1930s.
  - Unidentified people, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches; 2 items (Box 19, Folder 8)
    Unidentified male physician [Bill R.], matted black-and-white print, 1960.
  - Unidentified people, box size: 11.5 x 15 inches; 3 items (Box 19, Folder 9)
    Unidentified man [Glenn], mounted color print, after 1970
    unidentified physician in surgical scrubs, may be Director of Montreal Neurological Institute (image is gift from unnamed Director), color reproduction of painting
    Unidentified philosopher, engraving by Antonio Capellano after Florentine painter and engraver Giovanni Domenica Campiglia, 1800s?
- History of Medicine Picture File: Places Series, approx. 97 items
  Series mostly contains images of medical schools, colleges, and hospitals in England, Europe, and the United States. Series also contains images of other locations significant to medicine and/or the history of medicine. Arranged alphabetically by place name or title. In most cases, titles are from original image or folder.
  As with other series, the predominant formats are engravings, lithographs, and modern photographs, but there are other formats present such as postcards and negatives. Images are also often accompanied by a slide or negative reproduction created by Medical Library staff. Sizes range from under 10x12 inches up to 18x24 inches. The sizes of oversize boxes are given in the container inventory.
  - "...Amphiteatre anatomique construit sous le regne de Louis le Grand...," black-and-white photographic reproduction of 1694 engraving, 20th century (Box 11, Folder 1)
    Central focal point is the domed theater, and below, a panoramic view of the Seine and the equestrian statue of the king.
  - Beaumont Homestead, black-and-white sketch on card stock, Lebanon, Connecticut, Dr. H. T[homs], undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Beaumont Memorial, black-and-white photograph taken from the book, History of the APS: the Third Quarter Century, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Blue Sulphur Spring, Greenbrier County, Virginia, by Ed Beyer, from "Album of Virginia," color lithograph, 1857, box size: 18.5 x 24 inches (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Bologna, R. Arciginnasio, Sala Anatomica, black-and-white photographs on card stock, 1915, 2 items (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Boston General Hospital, color engraving, R. Goodacre, 1831 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Charleston, black-and-white copy of painting of Dr. John Lining's Apothecary Shop, undated, 2 copies (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Christ's Hospital, London, color engraving featuring two different angles of Christ's Hospital, undated, 2 items (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - City Lying-In Hospital, London, color engraving, undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Clendening Medical Library, University of Kansas, black-and-white photograph of the History of Medicine reading room, undated, 8x10 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - College of Medicine of the State University of Iowa, color painting on a pamphlet for Nupercainal Ciba, circa 1938 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Deaf and Dumb Asylum, London, color engraving, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - "Dining room at 32 Green St., Edinburgh, where chloroform was first used as an anaesthetic,1847," black-and-white photograph on cardstock, circa 1890s (Box 11, Folder 12)
    Place where chloroform was first used as an anaesthetic, 1847